Curriculum Vitae

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/acostahernan

E-mail: hernan0216@hotmail.com

Name: Carlos Hernán Acosta Rolla

phone: +59899702703
Website: hernan.engineer

Profile

Full stack developer with +10 years of experience. The tasks I enjoy the most are: backend development, data modeling, architectural design, and exploring the integration of new technologies and services. I am always trying to give my best to meet the expectations of the current quality market and new technologies.

Education

Bachelor degree in Engineering of Computer Science, Facultad de Ingeniería (Fing), Universidad de la República (UdeLaR). A 6-year plan that focuses on the formation of Computer Engineering in such areas as planning, developing and maintaining any computerized system.

Work experience

2020-2021

Overactive (Noodle), a CMS providing information about courses and programs from differents Universities on US, I participate as backend engineer designing, creating and maintaining new features for building a course platform using **python**, **flask rest json api**, **celery**, **postgres**, **elasticsearch** and many integrations with third party services like HubSpot CRM, Brightspace, Twillio, etc. All the infrastructure hosted on EC2 (AWS), CI with Travis and Jenkins.

2018-2020

The appraisal lane (TAL), real time used car trade network and communications platform that enables dealers to submit used cars for appraisal and receive cash orders. I participate as a backend engineer and lead in the notifications squad building a scalable and real time notifications system from scratch using kafka, python, jinja, asyncio, redis, ruby on rails, mongodb, firebase and socketio, the notifications system goals are building and sending web push, mobile push, in app and email notifications to the users in real time. After the notification system was ready for production I worked on the core squad building a

new real time chat service using **ruby on rails**, **redis**, **mongodb**, **elasticsearch and socketio**.

2015-2018

Consejo de Educación Secundaria (CES), the corporate system of CES provides services to 200K users approx. It has the goal to manage all the information about public high schools, administered by the government in Uruguay. I participate doing task of analysis, specification of requirements, architecture design, developing REST APIs and developing data analysis tasks over many data sources using tools like Python, Pandas, Numpy, Java, MYSQL, MongoDB, Memcached, Genexus Ev2, Linux CentOS, Apache Tomcat, RESTful APIS.

2010-2018

Daecpu (<u>DAECPU</u>), Daecpu is an organization that promotes Carnaval in Uruguay. I participated in Daecpu as a full stack engineer from product to devops. I used **Ionic framework** to build a hybrid mobile app and **Python ,Flask-Restful, Flask-Admin, Flask-Security, SQLAlchemy** over a **Postgres** database in the Backend. The app is hosted on **Heroku**, and there is an onsite server with CentOs with a daemon that processes different cron tasks from the Daecpu Call Center Server and interacts with the backend on **Heroku**.

2007-2014

Sistema Nacional de Información Ganadera (SNIG). SNIG is an Uruguayan system for the identification and traceability of cattle. SNIG provides a competitive advantage in a global market for Uruguayan meat. It has registered about 12 millions of animals and provides information for 65K users. I participate in the project as a business analyst and developer using Genexus, ArcGIS, SQL, Perl, SOAP web services.